Guide to the Jewish Heritage Foundation of North Carolina Records, 1750-2014 and undated RL.10159
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Subject files, 1750-2014 and undated; 3; 18.3 Linear Feet; 544.2 Megabytes
  - Topical subject files, 1750-2014 and undated; 4
    The folders in this subseries are arranged loosely alphabetically, reflecting the original order of the materials.
    - ["A Call for Candlesticks" by Dale Rosengarten], undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - A Portion of the People, 2000-2003 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Abernethy/NC, 1898, 1910 and undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - ADS [Advertisements], 1801-1936 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - African Americans - Slavery, 2003-2008 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - African Americans - Jewish Afro-Americans, 2002-2007 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - African Americans - Civil Rights, 1903, 1955-2012; 1 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - African Americans - Civil Rights, 1903, 1955-2012; 2 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - African Americans - Rabbis Race, 1955-1964, 1991-1998 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - African Americans - Bibliography, 1992, 1994 and undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - American Jewish Times, 1944, 1987 and undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - AJY [American Jewish Yearbook] - NC, 1899-1930 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - American Hebrew Academy, 20033-2008 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - American Israelite, 1898, 1920, 1922 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - American Israelite - Die Deborah, 1857 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - American synagogues: a photographic journey, 2008; 14254 Files; 544.2 Megabytes; e-book
      An extensive collection of United States synagogue photographs and history. Researched and compiled by Julian H. Preisler. Includes nearly 7200 image files (.jpg).
    - Antebellum, 2008 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Anti-Semitism, 1925, 1944, 1997-2009 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Anti-Semitism - Daniels - Philo Semitism, Morrison, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Artifacts, 1830s-1850s, 1999, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Artists, 2006-2008 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Asbill, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Baltimore, 1905, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Baltimore House - Epstein, undated (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - [Belah and Jake, A Garden of Memories], 1989; 1 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - [Belah and Jake, A Garden of Memories], 1989; 2 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Bibliography, 1982, 1998 and undated (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Biography, 1955-1997 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Blumenthal Home, 1921, 1964-1966, 2008 (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - B'nai B'rith, 1946-2011 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - [Brochures and programs for various Jewish organizations and events], 2009, 2012-2013 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - Business, Annual, 1955, 1977, 2002-2006 (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - Camps, 1936, 2004-2008 (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - Camp Blue Star, 1998, 2002, 2007 (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - [Photographs - Camp Blue Star], circa 1970s (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - The Blue Star Impact: Evaluating 50 Years of Blue Star's Mission, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - Calendar - Jewish War Veterans of the USA], 2000 (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - Calendars - Historic, undated (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - Cemeteries, 2004-2007 (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - American Jewish Identity Survey, 2001-2008 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Census, 1882, 1968-2008 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Census - Pew, 2008 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - NC Census, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Chabad, 2009 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Charleston, 2001-2013 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Christianity - Granade Family, 1750, 1788, 1907-2009 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Christian - Jewish Roots, 2007-2008 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Circuit Riding Rabbi - Blumenthal, 1948-1971 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Circuit Riding Rabbi - Marcus Polack - Mohel, 1895, 1989, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Circuit Riding, 1895-1900, 1958-2008 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Civil War - Bamberger, 1862-1920, 1979-2009 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Civil War, 2001-2010 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Clinton Rosh Hashanah Letter, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Colonial - Lopez, Platt, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Colonial, 1929-2008 and undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Colonial - Huhner, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - NC Constit - Occident, 1866-1867 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - NC Constitution - Jacob Henry, 1822-1887, 1946, 1984, 2001-2011 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - NC Crossroads, 2001 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - DH - Wilmington Artifacts, 1981, 2000-2002 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Davidson College, 1977, 2009 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Debutantes, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Delis, 1945, 1993, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Duke, 1980-2011; 1 of 3 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Duke, 1980-2011; 2 of 3 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Duke, 1980-2011; 3 of 3 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Dun Co. Credit Reports, undated (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - [Dun Credit], undated (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Dun, undated (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - [Dun Credit], undated (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Dun Credit - NC Bankruptcies, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill African Americans], 1986-1997 (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Beth El Cemetery], 1985 (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Beth El], 1920-1999; 1 of 3 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Beth El], 1920-1999; 2 of 3 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Beth El], 1920-1999; 3 of 3 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Bibliography], undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Biographical Files], undated; 1 of 19 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Biographical Files], undated; 2 of 19 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Biographical Files], undated; 3 of 19 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Biographical Files], undated; 4 of 19 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Biographical Files], undated; 5 of 19 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Biographical Files], undated; 6 of 19 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Biographical Files], undated; 7 of 19 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Biographical Files], undated; 8 of 19 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Biographical Files], undated; 9 of 19 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Biographical Files], undated; 10 of 19 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Biographical Files], undated; 11 of 19 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Biographical Files], undated; 12 of 19 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Biographical Files], undated; 13 of 19 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Biographical Files], undated; 14 of 19 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Biographical Files], undated; 15 of 19 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Biographical Files], undated; 16 of 19 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Biographical Files], undated; 17 of 19 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Biographical Files], undated; 18 of 19 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Biographical Files], undated; 19 of 19 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Biography, undated; 1 of 2 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Biography, undated; 2 of 2 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Book Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Census, 1992 and undated; 1 of 2 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Census, 1992 and undated; 2 of 2 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Community Lists, 1985-1991 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] CRC [Community Relations Council], 1982-1998; 1 of 3 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] CRC [Community Relations Council], 1982-1998; 2 of 3 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] CRC [Community Relations Council], 1982-1998; 3 of 3 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Cultural Programming, 1989-2000 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Demographics, 1910-2001; 1 of 3 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Demographics, 1910-2001; 2 of 3 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Demographics, 1910-2001; 3 of 3 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Federation, 1979-1999 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Friendship Circle, 1971-1982 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Holocaust Observance, 1989-2000 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Homelands Draft, 1993-2001 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Intermarriage, 1990-1999 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Israel, 1986-1999 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Jewish Community Day School, 1993-2000 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Durham-Chapel Hill Jewish Federation Minutes, Budget, 1978-2000; 1 of 2 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Durham-Chapel Hill Jewish Federation Minutes, Budget, 1978-2000; 2 of 2 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill Jewish Learning Experience], 1999 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Letters, 1986-1999 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Notes, undated (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Orgs, 1926-1949, 1978-2001 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] PJN [Progressive Jewish Network], 1985-1993 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Tobacco, 1894-1890, 1948, 1982 and undated (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Triangle Jewish Seminar, 1981, 1988-1999 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill] Young Judae, 1940-1942, 1952-1954 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - [Durham-Chapel Hill], 1944-1987 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Durham, 1887, 1990 and undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - [Durham's Jewish Sports Heroes], undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - [History of the Durham-Chapel Hill Jewish Community], 1986-1987 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Durham Library, 2005 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Encyclopedia, 1942, 1972, and undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Encycl Judaica, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Encyclopedia of American-Jewish History, 2004-2005 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Encyclopedia of Southern Religion, undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - NC - Fed/UJA, 1946-1951, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Fight Against Fear/JSR, 2005 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Film Festivals, 2009-2010 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Foodways, 1999-2010 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Foodways - Down Home Recipes, 2009-2010 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Foodways - Schewel, 1983, 1992, 2009 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - [Four Hundred Forty Six Years and Ten Days by Fred Hertz], undated (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - ["Freedom Fruits: The Americanization of an Old Time Religion" by Deborah Dash Moore], undated (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - From Pine Street to Watts Street: An Oral History of the Jews of Durham, North Carolina, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Gans, 2002, 2007 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Gertrude Weil's Address Book, 1920 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Gertrude Weil's Art Class Sketches, Smith College, 1898-1901 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - [Gertrude Weil - miscellaneous], 1923, 1932-1934, 2007, 2011 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - [Gertrude Weil - photographs], undated (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Weil Family Recipes, circa 1930s (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Israelite, 1950-1963 and undated (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Golden - UNC - Charlotte, 1949-1983, 2002-2008 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Golden, 1953-1970, 2002 (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Whitfield - Golden, 2006 (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Golden - SJHS, 2008 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Golden - Mecklenberg Co Library, 1956-1957 (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Hadassah, 2007-2010 (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Hahn-Fishblate, 2011 (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - Fishblate/Hahn, undated (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - Hasidim, 2008 (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - A Glimpse of NC Hillel, 1998-1999; 1 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - A Glimpse of NC Hillel, 1998-1999; 2 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - [B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundations National Leadership Council], 1993 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - Hillel, 1940-1952, 1986-2012; 1 of 2 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Hillel, 1940-1952, 1986-2012; 2 of 2 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - [Hillel] Task Force, 1985, 1992-1993 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Nat'l Hillel, 1990, 1993-1994 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - NC B'nai B'rith Association, 1963-1970 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - NC B'nai B'rith Hillel, 1935, 1949-1965 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - NC B'nai B'rith/Hillel Budget, 1961, 1966-1971 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - NC B'nai B'rith/Hillel Minute Book, 1971-1979 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - [NC Hillel], 1992-1994 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - NC Hillel Budget, 1983, 1991-1993 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - NC Hillel Dedication Guestbook, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - [NC Hillel Meeting Minutes], 1993-1994; 1 of 2 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - [NC Hillel Meeting Minutes], 1993-1994; 2 of 2 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - [NC Hillel Philanthropy], 1992-1994 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - NC Hillel Press Advertising, 1994-1995 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - North Carolina B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundation brochures, 1988-1992 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - [North Carolina Hillel], 2000-2008 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - North Carolina Hillel Press Packet, 1993-1994 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - North Carolina Hillel Press Packet, 1994-1995 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - North Carolina Hillel Press Packet, 1995-1996 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - North Carolina Hillel Press Packet, 1996-1997 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - [Color photographs of North Carolina Hillel Dedication], 2001; 1 of 4 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - [Color photographs of North Carolina Hillel Dedication], 2001; 2 of 4 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - [Color photographs of North Carolina Hillel Dedication], 2001; 3 of 4 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - [Color photographs of North Carolina Hillel Dedication], 2001; 4 of 4 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Holocaust - Hekler - Winston-Salem, undated (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Holocaust - Van Eeden, 1940-1943 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Holo II, 1984-1989, 2009-2011 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - NC Holocaust Council, 2005-2006 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Holocaust, 1979-2007 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - The Holocaust: A North Carolina Teacher's Resource, 1994 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Newspapers - NC - WWII, undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Humanistic Jews, 2009-2010 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Jewish Identity, 1985, 2004-2010 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Christians - Jewish Ancestry, 2008 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Southern-American Identity, 1878, 2007-2008 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Cohen-Blitzer - Belonging w/o Believing, 2008 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - IRO [Industrial Removal Office] - Charlotte, 1905, 1912-1913 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - IRO [Industrial Removal Office], 1905, 1913-1914 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Immigration, 2007-2009 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Muslim Dialogue, 1957, 1995, 2005-2010 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Interfaith, 1932-1980, 2000-2008 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Interfaith - Intermarriage, 2001, 2009 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Israel/NC, 1982-1985, 2000-2009 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Israel - Civil War, undated (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Jews in the American South (1860-1865), 1987; 1 of 2 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Jews in the American South (1860-1865), 1987; 2 of 2 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - ["Just Like One of Us" by Jack Bass], undated (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Katzen Family Genealogy, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Labor, undated (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Levitt, 1938 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - 1490 Listing of Marriages of Macon and Bibb County Georgia with One or both Spouse of Jewish Birth (1923-1998) (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Lox and Grits: Jewish Kitchens in Appalachia, 2009 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - [Love letters from Fred Hertz], undated (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Maps, 2003, 2005 and undated (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - Marcus, 1993 (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - Marcus - Small Towns, circa 1950s (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - Martin, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - McCarthy Era/Scales, 1955-1962 (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - Memphis, undated (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - Messianic Synagogues, 1973, 2001, 2007 (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - [Miscellaneous notes], undated (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - [Miscellaneous photographs], circa 1940s-1980s and undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - [Miscellaneous research materials], 1806, 1991-2012 (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - [Miscellaneous publications related to Southern Jewish Life], 2006-2013 (Box 27, Folder 36)
    - [Miscellaneous research materials], 1861-2014; 1 of 2 (Box 27, Folder 37)
    - [Miscellaneous research materials], 1861-2014; 2 of 2 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - [Miscellaneous research materials], 1898-2010; 1 of 3 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - [Miscellaneous research materials], 1898-2010; 2 of 3 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - [Miscellaneous research materials], 1898-2010; 3 of 3 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - [Miscellaneous research materials], 1913, 1946-2008 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - [Miscellaneous research materials], 1952, 1965, 2000-2009 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - [Miscellaneous research materials], 1988, 1998-2006 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Montgomery, 1871, 1875 and undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Mordecai, 2003-2006 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - My Father's People-Rubin, 1989, 2002 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Golden - NCHR, 1954-1955 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - NCMA, 2005-2013 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - NCSU, undated (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - NC Handbook - Judaism, undated (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - NC Lists, 1955, 1995, 2006-2008 and undated (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Klein - NC tour guide, 2009 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Natl Conf Christians and Jews - NC, 1940, 2009 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Naturalization Wake Co, 1856-1896 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Camin - Naturalization Index (1792-1862), 1989 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Naturalization/Alienation, 1852-1886 and undated (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - [Newspapers], 1925-1926 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Nobel, 2008 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - Norfolk, 2003, 2007 (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - [Obituaries], 2007-2013 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - Occident, 1867-1868 (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - Odeda, 1998-1999, 2001 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - Peddlers, 2008 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - Pelley, 1933, 1939 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - Politics, 1951-2011 (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - NC Rabbis, 1956-1967, 2002, 2008 (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - Rashi Press (S.C.) - "How to Respond to Missionaries", 1978 (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - Reconstruction, 2004 and undated (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - Reconstructionism, 1982, 1994, 2001-2005 (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - Research Triangle Park, 2006-2007 (Box 28, Folder 34)
    - Reynolds, undated (Box 28, Folder 35)
    - Richmond, 1986-1987, 1997-2007 (Box 28, Folder 36)
    - Rosenthal/Oettinger/Weil genealogy, 1936, 1976, 2000 (Box 28, Folder 37)
    - Rosenwald, 2001-2008 (Box 28, Folder 38)
    - Rosenzweig, 2003-2005 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Savannah, 2002-2004 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - ["Shalom Ya'll: The East European Jewish Experience in South Carolina" by Jenna Weissman Joselit], undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Shtetl, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Small Towns, 1970, 1977, 1988 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Speeches, undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Sports, 2006-2010 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - [Jewish Communities], 2008 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Soviet Jews, 1977, 1984 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Jewish Church, undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Small Town Orthodoxy, undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - State Directories, undated (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Southern Communities, 1987-2005 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - [Synagogues of North Carolina], 1997 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - North Carolina Synagogues, 2003, 2006 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Talks - Jews + Race, undated (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Talks - Portsmouth, 2010 and undated (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Talks - Powerpoint, undated (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Talks - Wake Co Lib, 2011 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Talks - Wilmington - Cosmopolitan, undated (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - [Temple House of Israel, Staunton, VA 125th Anniversary], 2001 (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Textile Industry, 2005, 2008 and undated (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - The Agudath Sholom Story: Breaking Apart and Coming Together, 1997 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - The Jewish Burials of Macon, Georgia (1844-1997) (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - The Story of the Nachamsons as Told by Jennie B. and The Nine Children, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Theater OR, 2002-2005 (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - ["This City is Our Jerusalem; This Happy Land Our Palestine" - essay by Eli Evans], undated (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - 350th, 2004 (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - UNC-Chapel Hill Hillel [Scrapbook], 1990-1991; 1 of 2 (Box 29, Folder 29)
    - UNC-Chapel Hill Hillel [Scrapbook], 1990-1991; 2 of 2 (Box 29, Folder 30)
    - UNC Asheville, 2008, 2010 (Box 29, Folder 31)
    - [Carolina Center for Jewish Studies], 2003-2010; 1 of 2 (Box 29, Folder 32)
    - [Carolina Center for Jewish Studies], 2003-2010; 2 of 2 (Box 29, Folder 33)
    - UNC, 1933-1938, 1959, 1980-2013; 1 of 2 (Box 29, Folder 34)
    - UNC, 1933-1938, 1959, 1980-2013; 2 of 2 (Box 29, Folder 34)
    - Vance - The Scattered Nation, 1878, 1904, 2008 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Washington, 2007-2008 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Weinstein (Dizun) Family Genealogy, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Who is My Neighbor?: Engaging Baptists and Jews in Dialogue, Thomas W. Allen, 2004 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Wildacres, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - [Photographs - Wildacres (North Cove, NC)], 1981-1984 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - World War II, 1942-1946, 1984, 2006-2007 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - World War II - Sam Marks, 1913, 1945, 1984 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - WWII Military Records, 1946 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Zionism, 1936-1944, 2002-2013 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Zionism - Israel, Cohen, 2008 (Box 30, Folder 11)
- Audiovisual, 1941-2011 and undated; 4; 2.8 Linear Feet 95 physical items
  The materials in the Audiovisual series consist of raw and edited video recordings related to the documentary film "Down Home: Jewish life in North Carolina" and other JHFNC/Rosenzweig Museum projects and exhibits, and various sound and video recordings related to Jewish history and culture, including documentary films, television programs, and religious services.
  The materials in this series are arranged into the following subseries: Down Home video recordings, Documentaries and television programs, and Other audiovisual material.
  - Down Home video recordings, 2002-2009 and undated; 5
    The video recordings in this subseries include raw and edited footage of individuals, groups, and locations featured in the documentary film "Down Home: Jewish life in North Carolina," which was produced by Video Dialog, Inc. Also included are recordings from other documentary projects that were produced by Video Dialog or obtained by the JHFNC for use in "Down Home." Note that addiitional interviews created for "Down Home" are located in the Jewish Heritage Foundation of North Carolina Oral History Collection also at the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
    The recordings are arranged chronologically.
    - Winston-Salem opening sequence, circa 2002; betacam-sp (Box 34, Video-cassette RL10159-Bcam-003)
      Footage from The Southern Jewish Store (2002) documentary by filmmaker Donna Schatz. Some of this footage appears in Down Home.
    - Winston-Salem [opening sequence], circa 2002; VHS (Box 32, Video-cassette RL10159-VHS-029)
    - Durham Jewish Day Ctr., 2002 August 24; betacam-sp, 1 of 2 (Box 34, Video-cassette RL10159-Bcam-001)
      Footage of Durham Jewish Day Center, possibly used for Down Home.
    - Durham Jewish Day Ctr., 2002 August 24; betacam-sp, 2 of 2 (Box 34, Video-cassette RL10159-Bcam-002)
    - Down home: Jewish life in North Carolina - preview, circa 2003; VHS (Box 32, Video-cassette RL10159-VHS-033)
    - Down home: Jewish life in North Carolina - preview and vignettes, 2003; computer optical disc
      Includes Hannah Block and Jerry Levin vignettes.
    - Down home trailer, 2005 September 23; DVD (Box 33, Video-disc RL10159-DVD-018)
    - Matzoh ball gumbo - Marcie Cohen Ferris, 2006 March 27; digital betacam, 1 of 3 (Box 34, Video-cassette RL10159-Dbcam-001)